Okay, so this strategy
I'm going to give
you is faster, easier,
and more effective than
anything else you'll ever
try. And it works
like this. So imagine
all you needed to
do to make a
million dollars is open
a door. But the
catch is this, there's
100 doors to choose
from. 99 % of
them are going to
punch you in the
face when you open
them. And then the
one that doesn't is
going to hand you
a bag with $10
,000 of cash in.
If you found the
one that gave you
10K, would you keep
opening the others to
make your million? Or
would you just keep
opening the 10K door?
Now, I know that
sounds absolutely ridiculous, but
it's what most people
do with their YouTube
channels. They try something
that works and then
immediately try something new
and their viewers punch
them in the face
because they don't want
that new thing. They
just want the thing
that brought them to
the channel, meaning they
waste their time and
get worse results. So
the strategy I'm going
to give you for
growing channels is going
to get you punched
in the face. Many
painful times until we
find the thing that
works. And then all
we do is repeat
it. So let me
show you how powerful
this and how it
works. So it's January,
2025, and I wanted
to reposition my channel
like many of you
might be doing right
now. And to do
that, I came up
with this 90 day
challenge where I was
going to post two
high quality videos a
week following my fail
as fast as you
can system. So to
start the challenge, I
did the research I'm
going to show you
how to do and
then turned what I
discovered into different video
ideas. The idea being
I'd try lots of
different titles, lots of
thumbnails, and I'd try
to do a lot
of different things. I
tried out a lot
of different formats to
get some juicy data
that I could then
learn lessons from and
harness. So I tried
out this format. This
is just a short
video that went over
the broad steps of
a process without going
that deep in under
10 minutes. And I
call that a short
process video. Boom. It
blew up with views
and sales and emails.
And you know what?
I thought it was
going to flop. So
that was pretty cool.
Then all I did
was I turned it
into a template and
I made it again.
And again and again.
So if you look
at the funnels on
screen right now, you're
going to notice they
all have the same
title structure and a
very similar image. And
that is what it
means to repeat what
works in the packaging.
So can you see
it's pretty much the
same photo too. Often
I'm just using different
t -shirt colors from
Photoshop. And that is
where your massive time
saving is. Now, you
might be thinking, well,
hang on, Ed, a
couple of them didn't
perform as well. So
why did you keep
doing them? Your system
doesn't work. Well, that's
actually my fault, not
the templates, because they're
not the same. They're
not the same. Because
in the videos that
didn't do as well,
I made mistakes which
put off the viewers.
But using my system,
I'll eventually teach you.
I realized what they
were. So I learned
the lesson about the
viewers and then turned
that into a win
because I'm not going
to do it again.
And that is how
we grow. But that's
just the packaging. When
this video did well,
I thought, well, why
bother writing new intros
for the others? So
I just took the
intro and made that
a template. I'll show
you some of them
on screen right now.
Just pause to read
them so you can
see they're very similar.
But also because that
first video was so
effective, I thought, well,
why bother coming up
with a new script
for the next one?
So I just turned
the script into a
template and added some
rules to follow for
the best way to
create this type of
video ongoing. And as
I learned more lessons
repeating these formats over
and over again, I
just added them to
my little rule book
so I could refine
them. Now, I'm going
to be giving every
single one of you
all of the templates
in the coming modules,
so you don't have
to do any of
this yourself, by the
way. But what you
have to understand is
the first video in
this series took me
three hours to come
up with just the
thumbnail and title. The
scripts took a very
long time too, because
it was all a
new experiment for me.
But using the repeat
what works template system,
by the time I
use it for this
video here, the entire
thing from start to
finish took me two
hours. It's the quickest
video I've ever made.
And look how many
flipping views it got.
In fact, look at
how many views all
of them got. But
that's just one style
of video on my
channel. The whole point
of my system is
you find three different
formats that work, which
you then keep repeating.
And then you have
to find the one
that works. So that's
what this testing period
revealed. Look, you can
see here it worked.
Again, this format of
video generated massive sales,
which is the most
important metric. So I
just made it a
template, wrote a rule
book in the same
way, and then I
went and used the
same thumbnail photo pretty
much every time. And
then the intros and
script format is almost
identical too. All of
these performed amazing for
the business, apart from
this one, which was
totally my fault. But
the lesson I learned
as to why this
didn't do so well,
was that it was
a lot of work.
And once again, the
first video took days
to make, but the
last one took like
three hours. But it
doesn't stop there. We
then have this type
of video format. And
again, the sales of
this were just next
level, and the views
were pretty good too.
So I did it
again. I just templated
the thing and then
refined the rules and
the template as I
learned more. And again,
it generated more sales
and emails. So just
keep doing it. Now
to show you what
this looks like, let's
just put some X
-ray specs on my
channel and I'll color
code each video. So
you see that? All
of those color ones
are just me repeating
what works. But what
I want you to
pay close attention to,
these ones here are
not colored. That was
me trying something in
between the proven formats.
And they absolutely suck
for views and sales
because those type of
videos, they weren't what
the fans and the
return viewers want from
me. It's actually the
wrong wrapping paper and
the wrong box for
them now. Now, even
though I've just showed
you the power of
this, admit it, you're
still thinking to yourself,
but Ed, won't viewers
think you're being lazy
just repeating what works?
But answer me this,
if I take away
these colored blocks, can
you tell it's just
three or four videos
doing the same thing
over and over again?
No, because we spaced
them out, right? So
our strategy is this,
we post videos based
on the research I'm
going to get you
to do, and then
fail as fast as
you can until one
performs above average for
us. When that happens,
we then reuse it
as a template and
repeat. It in three
to four videos time.
It's my goal to
have three templated video
formats based on what
viewers already know and
love from my channel.
And then every fourth,
I try something new
to reduce the risk
of a flop. Then
if this fourth video
performs above average, we
template it and repeat
it. Now, when that
happens, you can replace
one of the other
three to keep the
channel fresh and progressing
because sometimes these formats
die out, or you
can just have four
templates you repeat and
then experiment on the
fifth. Just keep in
mind that any, any
video with any of
the four videos, you
can try to get
one out of the
other and then repeat
it. experimental video that
leaves the expectations of
your viewers just a
bit is significantly less
likely to perform. And
then what happens is
if you do this
in your channel, your
average video performance is
steadily going to increase,
which is the best
way to grow a
channel and a business.
And the cool thing
is if you're an
experienced channel, there's a
very strong chance you
already have your free
formats just waiting for
you to repeat. But
what if you are
new or small? How
can you repeat what
worked if your top
videos only has 100
views? Well, this is
what you do. So
remember this chart from
earlier in the course,
the yellows are videos
that grow channels. What's
going to happen is
you're going to test
all the formats I
teach in the coming
modules one by one
until one shows a
sign of life that's
strong for your own
channel. So let's say
you're getting 90 views
a video to start
and a new one
gets 700. That becomes
your first repeat what
works template, but you
just try to improve
on the content more
each time. And then
you test new formats
for the next three
and it is very
likely you don't find
anything that works for
a long time because
if you're new, you're
only going to get
trapped in the same
format for the next
three. So you're going
to have to repeat
what works. So remember
this chart, things will
get better so long
as you stick to
my plan. But the
transformation to Hulk in
this period is going
to be max pain.
So this is the
strategy. It's the fail
as fast as you
can system where we
just test, learn and
repeat what works. And
in the next video,
we're going to look
at how we're going
to research to find
new ideas that can
grow the channel, as
well as look at
what we can just
repeat on your own
that's already there. We're
also going to use
a lot of AI
to speed all of
this up for you.
And then you're going
to come up with
the next four video
titles and thumbnails as
you start to discover
patterns as to the
type of words and
images and formats your
viewers want more of.
And then after that,
I'm going to give
you the script template
for each type of
format. And the goal
here is to test
them out over the
medium term to level
up and establish what
your viewers love.